{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Cstr works on the principle of:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Heat Transfer",
        "b": "Mass transfer",
        "c": "Both heat and mass transfer",
        "d": "None of the mentioned"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Accumulation of mass in the reactor is given by:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Accumulation=[IN]-[Out]-[Generation]",
        "b": "Accumulation=[IN]-[Out]+[Generation]",
        "c": "Accumulation=[IN]+[Out]-[Generation]",
        "d": "Accumulation=[Out]-[IN]+[Generation]"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Assumptions on which the CSTR works is/are:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Uniform mixing of the cooling fluid and reactor fluid",
        "b": "Heat transfer coefficient to the reactor jacket is constant",
        "c": "Mean heat capacity is constant",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Arrhenius rate law k=Aexp(-Ea/RT) Ea represents.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Frequency factor",
        "b": "Activation energy",
        "c": "Rate of the reaction",
        "d": "Constant"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you understand by quasi steady state.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A permanent steady state",
        "b": "An unstable state",
        "c": "A state where the reaction rests for predestined time and then jumps back to steady state.",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these sets can act as the control parameters of the polymerization of styrene?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Feed rate of monomer,initiator,temperature of cooling fluid",
        "b": "Activation energy of the reaction",
        "c": "Density of reactor fluid and cooling fluid",
        "d": "None of above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you understand by the term polymerization",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Two or more simple compounds react to form a complex molecule",
        "b": "Two or more monomers react in a chemical reaction to form a large polymer",
        "c": "The large molecule formed by reacting of simple molecules generally containg a repeating structure",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the steps of the radical polymerization",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Termination-propagation-initiation",
        "b": "Initiation-propagation-termination",
        "c": "Initiation-termination-propagation",
        "d": "Propagation-initiation-termination"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Heat transfer expression in the CSTR is given by",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Heat accumulation=[heat in]-[heat out]+[rate of heat generation]+[heat transfer]",
        "b": "Heat accumulation=[heat out]-[heat in]+[rate of heat generation]+[heat transfer]",
        "c": "Heat accumulation=[heat in]-[heat out]-[rate of heat generation]+[heat transfer]",
        "d": "Heat accumulation=[heat in]-[heat out]+[rate of heat generation]-[heat transfer]"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The order of the reaction of polymerization of styrene is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Zero",
        "b": "First",
        "c": "Third",
        "d": "Second"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
